lol-europe.com 2012-06-30

# Privacy Policy | LoL - League of Legends

Last Modified: April 12, 2011

Riot Games, Inc., a Delaware corporation, its subsidiary, Riot Games, Ltd., an Irish limited company, and its other subsidiaries (collectively, hereinafter referred to as "us," "we," or "Riot Games") are committed to respecting the privacy rights of the customers, visitors, and other users of Riot Games’ free-to-play computer game, League of Legends (the “ **Game** ”) and its related website, [www.leagueoflegends.com](http://www.leagueoflegends.com/) (the “ **Site** ”). We created this Privacy Policy (this " **Policy** ") to give you, the user, confidence as you visit and use the Site or the Game, and to demonstrate our commitment to fair information practices and the protection of privacy. By visiting the Site or using the Game, you consent to our collection, use, storage, deletion and disclosure of information relating to you as set forth in this Policy. This Policy is only applicable to the Site and the Game, and not to any other third-party websites that you may be able to access from the Site, each of which may have data collection and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Policy.

## I. INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE PRACTICES

### A. What Basic Information Does Riot Games Collect?

We only collect personally identifiable information from you on a voluntary basis, and you may visit areas on the Site without providing us with such. However, in order to use certain parts of the Site and/or log-on to play the Game, you will be required to create an account by providing us your email address and selecting a unique username and password (an “ **Account** ”). For age verification purposes, we also ask for your birthday during the Account creation process. In the course of maintaining your Account, you might also be asked to participate in online surveys about the Game, or in other Game-related promotional contests, participation in which is entirely voluntary. You might also desire to contact our customer support team via the “support” tab found on the Site. In participating in such promotional activities or in contacting customer support, you might be requested to provide additional information beyond your email address, including your name, birthday, and other contact information. In operating the Site or otherwise offering the Game, we might also request other information from you, including hardware specs, game experience, refer-a-friend, and other demographic information that might be associated with your personal information, such as your gender, hobbies, occupation, platform preferences, and other game ownership information.

Please note that in utilizing certain areas of the Site (e.g. purchasing merchandise) or the Game (e.g. purchasing Riot Points), you will be requested to provide additional information in order to complete a purchase, such as your name, address and credit card or other payment information. This information is provided solely to a third party payment provider, and none of this information is collected or stored by Riot Games. Please see Section IV below regarding how third parties working on behalf of Riot Games use your personal information.

### B. What Additional Information Does Riot Games Collect?

(1) AUTOMATIC COLLECTION. Our servers automatically recognize visitors' domain names and internet protocol (IP) addresses (the number assigned to computers on the Internet). In addition, your web browser or Game software may transmit to Riot Games certain geographic information or other information regarding your computer, including its capabilities, hardware specs and game data processing. No personal information about you is revealed in this process. The Site may also gather anonymous "traffic data" that does not personally identify you, but that may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer.

(2) COOKIES. From time to time, we may use the standard "cookies" feature of major browser applications that allows us to store a small piece of data on your computer about your visit to the Site. We do not set any personally identifiable information in cookies, nor do we employ any data capture mechanisms on the Site other than cookies. Cookies help us learn which areas of the Site are useful and which areas need improvement. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser. However, if you choose to disable this function, your experience at the Site may be diminished and some features may not work as they were intended.

### C. What Does Riot Games Do With Collected Information?

(1) PERSONAL INFORMATION. We will not share your personal information with any third parties without your consent, except as necessary to provide you with the services offered by us or to comply with the law. We may use your personal information to verify your identity or to check your qualifications, to inform you of any changes to the Site or Game, or to send you additional information about Riot Games. We may also use your information to contact you should we believe that you are in violation of the [Terms of Use Agreement](http://www.leagueoflegends.com/legal/termsofuse) (“ **Terms of Use** ”) or the [End User License Agreement](http://www.leagueoflegends.com/legal/eula) (“ **EULA** ”).

(2) ANONYMOUS INFORMATION. We use anonymous information to analyze the Site traffic, but we do not examine this information for individually identifying information. In addition, we may use anonymous IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our servers, to administer the Site, or to display the content according to your preferences. Traffic and transaction information may also be shared with business partners and advertisers on an aggregate and anonymous basis.

(3) USE OF COOKIES. We may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit the Site, or for other purposes. Promotions or advertisements displayed on the Site may contain cookies. We do not have access to or control over information collected by outside advertisers on the Site.

(4) DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION. We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Riot Games or its parent company, subsidiaries or affiliates, (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Riot Games or the users of the Site or Game, or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the safety of the public or users of the Site or Game.

(5) SALE OF INFORMATION. In order to accommodate changes in our business, we may sell or buy portions of our company or other companies or assets, including the information collected through the Site or otherwise collected in connection with the Game. If Riot Games or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will be one of the assets transferred to the acquirer. Should such an event occur, we will use reasonable means to notify you, either through email and/or a prominent notice on the Site.

(6) ACCESS TO INFORMATION. Unfortunately, we do not maintain any procedures for you to review or request changes to the information that we collect about you, except that you may request that we remove all information about you from our database by contacting us in accordance with Section VIII.A below.

### D. Notice Concerning Children

**PLEASE NOTE** : We are a general audience site, and do not direct any of our content specifically at children under 13 years of age. We understand and are committed to respecting the sensitive nature of children's privacy online, and as such do not knowingly collect any personal information from any user under age 13. If we learn or have reason to suspect that a Site or Game user is under age 13, we will promptly delete any personal information in that user's Account.

## II. SECURITY

The Site and the Game have security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information that we obtain from you. We store your personal information on our servers, which are located in secured facilities with restricted access, and protected by protocols and procedures designed to ensure the security of such information. In addition, we restrict access to personal information to Riot Games employees, independent contractors and agents who need to know this information in order to develop, operate and maintain the Site and the Game. All Riot Games personnel who have access to this information are trained in the maintenance and security of such information. However, no server, computer or communications network or system, or data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect user information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us through the use of the Game or the Site and we make no assurances about our ability to prevent any such loss or misuse to you or to any third party. You acknowledge and agree that you provide such information and engage in such transmissions at your own risk.

## III. WEBSITE AREAS BEYOND OUR CONTROL

### A. Public Forums and In-Game Chat Text

The Site includes a section for interactive “forums” in the form of message boards (the “ **Forums** ”) to which users with an Account and an in-Game Summoner name may post. Additionally, within the Game, you can participate in real-time interactive chat (“Chat”) with other players. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in the Forums or Chat becomes public information in which you relinquish any expectation of privacy. Remember that Riot Games asks that you not disclose any personal information when posting in the Forums or in Chat, and you should exercise caution when deciding what information to share. We reserve the right, but shall have no obligation, to monitor your use of the Forums or Chat.

### B. Third Party Websites

The Site may contain links to other websites. If you choose to visit other websites, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those other websites, and it is your responsibility to review the privacy policies at those websites to confirm that you understand and agree with their policies.

### IV. SERVICE PROVIDERS

We may share your personal information with service providers that we engage for the purpose of processing information on our and your behalf, such as to fulfill product orders, collect billing information and process payments. While providing services for us, these companies may access your personal information. Any financial information submitted, however, such as your credit card information and billing address, is provided solely to the third-party payment provider, and none of this information is collected by, shared with, or stored by Riot Games.

To the extent applicable, we require these entities to comply with this Policy and appropriate confidentiality and security measures. In certain instances, some entities also have their own policies regarding privacy and information protection, and these policies can be located in the areas of the Site or the Game where you are interacting with such third-party service providers.

### V. THE TRIBUNAL

Riot Games has empowered its community of users (the “ **Community** ”) to policy the compliance of other users with Riot Games’ policies as they apply to in-Game behavior. Community members, including you as a user, are allowed to report players and submit descriptions of activity and action of certain users within the Game, and collectively determine if that particularly user was in compliance with all of the Riot Games policies relating to user conduct.

Consistent with the terms of [The Riot Games Tribunal Policy](http://www.leagueoflegends.com/legal/tribunal), all Chat will be recorded by Riot Games and stored for a period determined by Riot Games in its sole discretion, which period Riot Games may change from time to time. Should your in-Game actions be reported by another user, and should your case come before The Tribunal, the entire Chat log from that particular reported Game session will automatically be included in The Tribunal report and available for viewing by randomly selected members of the Community that participate in The Tribunal. As stated above, please take care to not provide any personally identifiable information in the Chat, understanding that the Chat is public information in which you do not have an expectation of privacy. Notwithstanding the above, Riot Games will not use any personally identifiable information that might appear within the Chat for any purposes whatsoever, beyond the automatic posting of the Chat log to the Tribunal report.

## VI. DISPUTE RESOLUTION

### A. Dispute Resolution Outside The European Union

If you are a resident of any country not a current member of the European Union, you agree that should any dispute or claim arise out of, or relate to, this Policy (“ **Claim** ”), you will attempt in good faith to negotiate a written resolution of the Claim directly with us. You agree that if the matter remains unresolved for thirty (30) days after one party has provided written notice of the Claim to the other party, all parties shall join in mediation services in Los Angeles, California with a mutually agreed mediator in an attempt to resolve the dispute. Should you file any arbitration claims, or any administrative or legal actions without first having attempted to resolve the matter by mediation, then you agree that you will not be entitled to recover attorneys’ fees, even if you would otherwise be entitled to them.

Riot Games will send its notice to the address it has on file to the extent that you have provided additional contact information to Riot Games (e.g. by participating in a promotional or survey, or contacting a customer services representative). Otherwise, Riot Games will send its notice to the email address associated with your Account. You will send your notice to Riot Games, Inc., 10736 Jefferson Blvd #622, Culver City, California, 90230, Attn: Legal Department. Please note that this informal resolution procedure does not suspend any statutory limitation periods applicable to the bringing of a Claim.

### B. Dispute Resolution Within The European Union

If you are a resident of any country that is a current member of the European Union, should you have a dispute or claim arising out of, or relating to, this Policy, you may report your claim to the European Union Data Protection Authorities located in your jurisdiction.

## VII. SAFE HARBOR CERTIFICATION

Riot Games complies with the U.S. - EU Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from the European Union member countries and Switzerland. Riot Games has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Riot Games’ certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

## VIII. CONTACT INFORMATION AND POLICY UPDATES

### A. Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Policy, our practices regarding your personal information related to the Site or Game, or if you would like to have us remove your information from our database, please feel contact us at [privacy@riotgames.com](mailto:privacy@riotgames.com). Please note that the deletion of your data will lead to the termination of your Account and applicable services. However, also note that when you delete your Account, we may retain your Account information for a reasonable period of time afterward for the purpose of internal account management and fraud prevention activities.

### B. Updates and Changes

We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update, or modify this Policy, simply by posting such change, update, or modification on the Site and without any other notice to you. Any such change, update, or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site. It is your responsibility to review this Policy from time to time to ensure that you continue to agree with all of its terms.

BY USING THE SITE AND/OR THE GAME, YOU SIGNIFY THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTAND AND AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT USE THE SITE OR THE GAME.

### C. Additional Policies

There are additional Riot Games legal policies that govern your use of the Site and the Game. Please take time to review and familiarize yourself with both the [Terms of Use](http://www.leagueoflegends.com/legal/termsofuse) and the [EULA](http://www.leagueoflegends.com/legal/eula).
